<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reviews</title>
    <description>Review on network and security papers.</description>
    <link>http://mwzhang.com/reviews/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://mwzhang.com/reviews/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 16:28:03 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 16:28:03 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: Avant-guard: Scalable and vigilant switch flow management in software-defined networks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avant-guard&lt;/strong&gt; propose two ideas in the paper:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Connection migration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Condition triggers for rule processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;connection-migration&quot;&gt;Connection Migration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The connection migration box mainly focused on solving the problems of SYN flood in SDN environment.
The SYN flood will trigger a &lt;code&gt;packet_in&lt;/code&gt; message flood from the SDN switch to SDN controller.
While the SDN switch waiting for the reply from the SDN controller,
the cache of the switch is vulnerable to exhaustion and thus could potentially crash the switch entirely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main idea of solving this problem is to process the TCP SYN separately.
It will first classify the traffic and remove all unrecognized TCP FIN or RST packets.
Then the migration box itself will do the handshake with the source.
After a full handshake, it will then report to the controller and make connection with the real destination.
After the controller replies, the migration box will work as a relay, forwarding all the traffic to the destination.
&lt;strong&gt;Essentially, the migration box works as a men-in-the-middle, and filter out SYN flood messages without involving the controller.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The delaying mode of the connection migration only start the contacting the controller when it receives the traffic content after the handshake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standard connection migration scenario:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/7cGUTxX.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/7cGUTxX.png&quot; alt=&quot;mc&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standard connection migration delay mode scenario:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/6npXjQe.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/6npXjQe.png&quot; alt=&quot;mcdelay&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;actuating-trigger&quot;&gt;Actuating Trigger&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of the &lt;code&gt;actuating trigger&lt;/code&gt; is simple as putting a condition check in SDN switch.
After the matching of flows complete, the SDN switch will also collect some basic statistics and check the condition.
If the condition is met, the SDN switch will run a call-back function that can notify and react to the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This idea can be used for close-to-real-time anomaly detection without pulling/polling the switches. 
However, this design requires changes to the existing SDN switches and adds additional component in between the flow processing procedure, and thus could face hurdles in deployment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example scenario of the actuating trigger:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/sHEuvAa.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/sHEuvAa.png&quot; alt=&quot;trigger&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bib entry:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@article{shin2013avant-guard,
	author = {Shin, S and Yegneswaran, V and Porras, P and Gu, G},
	isbn = {9781450324779},
	journal = {Proceedings of the 2013 ACM \ldots}
	title = 
	year = {2013}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://mwzhang.com/reviews/2015/09/shin2013avant-guard.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mwzhang.com/reviews/2015/09/shin2013avant-guard.html</guid>
        
        <category>SDN</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
        <category>paper review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: SPHINX: Detecting Security Attacks in Software-Defined Networks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;SPHINX is a anomaly detection application that sit in between the SDN controller and the SDN switches.
SPHINX aims to construct a trust-worthy topology graph, &lt;em&gt;flow graph&lt;/em&gt;, using the controller’s OpenFlow messages,
and detect anomalous messages from the SDN swithches using such graph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;theat-model&quot;&gt;Theat Model&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OpenFlow messges from the controller to the switches are trustworthy.
But all the messages from the switches to the controller could be forged by a malicious switch or in some cases by the hosts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;flow-graph&quot;&gt;Flow Graph&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flow graph is constructed only using &lt;code&gt;FLOW_MOD&lt;/code&gt; messages issued by the trusted controller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The procedure is as the follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/uJVbNbF.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/uJVbNbF.png&quot; alt=&quot;flowgraph&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sphinx&quot;&gt;SPHINX&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the flow graph built, the SPHINX raises alerts when it detects untrusted entities triggering &lt;em&gt;changes&lt;/em&gt; to existing flow behavior,
or the flow violates any administrator-specified security policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/2Ae1z7z.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/2Ae1z7z.png&quot; alt=&quot;sphinx&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://mwzhang.com/reviews/2015/09/dhawan2015sphinx.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mwzhang.com/reviews/2015/09/dhawan2015sphinx.html</guid>
        
        <category>SDN</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
        <category>paper review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: Revisiting Traffic Anomaly Detection using Software Defined Networking</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;anomaly-detection-in-data-plane&quot;&gt;Anomaly Detection in Data Plane&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data plane anomaly detection can be deployed at core network,
or at end-point network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paper [mehdi2011revisiting] argues that the deployment of ADS at core network suffers from the following two problems:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;low detection rate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;slow in processing speed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two problems disabled ADS from being deployed at core network.
As a result, the deployment schemes should be then more focused on end-point networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;anomaly-detection-algorithms&quot;&gt;Anomaly Detection Algorithms&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four algorithms mentioned and implemented in this paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;threshold-random-walk-with-credit-based-rate-limiting&quot;&gt;Threshold Random Walk with Credit Based Rate Limiting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key idea of this algorithm is to keep track of all the un-established TCP handshakes.
The timed out handshakes or RSTs will result in an increment of suspicious value.
The higher the suspicious values are, the lower the rate will be limited to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rate-limiting&quot;&gt;Rate Limiting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delay all new connections unless they are in working set.
Only install rules if the traffic successfully finished the handshakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;maximum-entropy-detector&quot;&gt;Maximum Entropy Detector&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The method is divided into training phase and operation phase.
During the training phase, the algorithm use maximum entropy estimation to establish a based line benign distribution for each class of packets (2,348 classes in total).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then during the operation phase, use Kullback-Leibler divergence measure of estimate the entropy.
An alarm is raised if a packet KL divergence exceeds a threshold K, more than H times in the last W windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The maximum entropy detector requires to examine &lt;strong&gt;all packets&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;netad&quot;&gt;NETAD&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NETAD is a rule-based filtering method that can filter out &lt;em&gt;“uinterested traffic”&lt;/em&gt;.
During implementation, each new packets will be passed to the controller, and the controller check the rules.
If the packet passes the rules, then the corresponding flows will be added to the switch to allow the traffic passing through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This method also requires to examine &lt;strong&gt;all packets&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;data-set&quot;&gt;Data Set&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We decided to collect our own benign and attack
datasets and make them available for repeatable performance evaluations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;benign-traffic&quot;&gt;Benign Traffic&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benign traffic was collected in three different locations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Home Network&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Small Office/ Home Office (SOHO)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Internet Service Provider&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;attack-traffic&quot;&gt;Attack Traffic&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;we launched (TCP SYN), DoS (TCP SYN)
and fraggle (UDP flood) simultaneously from three end hosts in our research lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;result&quot;&gt;Result&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The evaluation result shows that the deployment scheme at end-point networks has better accuracy than on ISP. 
The result details shown in the figure below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/ywQx9nN.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/ywQx9nN.png&quot; alt=&quot;result&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authors also evaluated the implement on efficiency on the four parameters:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Percent of total packets that pass through the controller&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Average rate of packets passing through the controller&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Average number of flows in the switch’s flow table&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peak size of the switch’s flow table&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result is shown below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/2DQk49r.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/2DQk49r.png&quot; alt=&quot;efficiency&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bib entry:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
@article{Mehdi2011,
	author = {Mehdi, Syed Akbar and Khalid, Junaid and Khayam, Syed Ali},
	isbn = {978-3-642-23643-3},
	issn = {0302-9743},
	journal = {Entropy},
	keywords = {anomaly detection,network security,openflow,programmable networks,software defined net,working},
	pages = {1--20},
	title = ,
	volume = {6961},
	year = {2011}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://mwzhang.com/reviews/2015/08/mehdi2011revisiting.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mwzhang.com/reviews/2015/08/mehdi2011revisiting.html</guid>
        
        <category>SDN</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>anomaly detection</category>
        
        
        <category>paper review</category>
        
        <category>sdn</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: Malicious BGP Hijacks : Appearances Can Be Deceiving</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The authors mentioned a key idea in the paper:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Correlation of suspicious routing events with malicious activities
is insufficient to evidence harmful BGP hijacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This arugument just went against the &lt;code&gt;duan2011empirical&lt;/code&gt; paper’s main methodology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;system-design&quot;&gt;System Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authors use all four types of data methods in the design of the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;active&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;passive&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;control-plane&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;RIR&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;RIPE BGP Updates&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;data-plane&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;SpamTrap&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;Munich’s Scientific Network&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/CEYjKdA.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/CEYjKdA.png&quot; alt=&quot;arch&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;benign-moas&quot;&gt;Benign MOAS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authors defined the benign MOAS as&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;multiple origins of a prefix share a direct AS-level link&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;uptime of the prefix is larger than a threshold T&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They found out that a lot of the “hijacks” or malicious MOAS are actually benign or unable to be classified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bib entry:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@article{vervier2014malicious,
    author = {Vervier, Pierre-antoine and Jacquemart, Quentin and Schlamp, Johann and Thonnard, Olivier and Carle, Georg and Urvoy-keller, Guillaume and Biersack, Ernst and Dacier, Marc},
    isbn = {9781479920037},
    pages = {890--895},
    title = ,
    year = {2014}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://mwzhang.com/reviews/2015/08/vervier2014malicious.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mwzhang.com/reviews/2015/08/vervier2014malicious.html</guid>
        
        <category>BGP</category>
        
        <category>hijack</category>
        
        <category>attack</category>
        
        
        <category>paper review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: Losing Control of the Internet: Using the Data Plane to Attack the Control Plane</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;key-idea&quot;&gt;Key idea&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The BGP routers are vulnerable to Coordinate Croos Plane Session Termination (CXPST) attack.
The vulnerability is based on the fact that the control-plane and data-plane use the same medium.
A flooded medium could jam the control-plane messages and trigger the connected router to believe that the BGP sessions has failed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attackers could explote the vulnerability to disconnect a pair of routers.
The disconnected routers will thus generate a surge of BGP updates
that will spread across the Internet’s core routers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In this paper we show how an adversary can attack multiple BGP sessions simultaneously
and measure the impact these session failures have on the control plane of the Internet.
We directly simulate the BGP activity resulting from this attack
and compute the impact those messages have on router processing loads.
Through simulations we show that botnets on the order of 250, 000 nodes
can increase processing delays from orders of microseconds to orders of hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key tasks for CXPST to work:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;select correct BGP session to maximize the number of BGP updates it will genreate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;direct traffic to the target link.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;minimize the impact of falp dampening mechanisms on the attack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/OKvQD5b.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/OKvQD5b.png&quot; alt=&quot;topo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paper is still vague about how they could actually direct the traffic to the target link.
The evaluation is also done in simulation, which could be impractical in real-world cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bib entry:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@article{schuchard2010losing,
    author = {Schuchard, Max and Mohaisen, Abedelaziz and Kune, Denis Foo and Hopper, Nicholas and Kim, Yongdae and Vasserman, Eugene Y},
    isbn = {9781450302449},
    journal = {Proceedings of the 17th \ldots},
    pages = {726--728},
    title = ,
    url = {http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=1866411},
    year = {2010}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://mwzhang.com/reviews/2015/08/schuchard2010losing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mwzhang.com/reviews/2015/08/schuchard2010losing.html</guid>
        
        <category>BGP</category>
        
        <category>attack</category>
        
        
        <category>paper review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: Concurrent Prefix Hijacks : Occurrence and Impacts</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;key-obseravation&quot;&gt;Key Obseravation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simutaneous originations of prefixes of many other networks is suspicious.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But when a network simultaneously originates prefixes of many other networks,
it is highly likely to be a real hijack
since operational arrangements with many different networks
are unlikely to take effect at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;methodology&quot;&gt;Methodology&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first keep track of the &lt;strong&gt;origin changes&lt;/strong&gt; from any single monitor on the Internet.
Then it compile the results from many monitors together to form a global view of the origin changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it will estimate the legitimate changes, and rule them out from the dataset.
The authors considered the following cases legitimate changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;stable AS set&lt;/strong&gt;:
  the set of long-lived origin ASes for each prefix&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;related set&lt;/strong&gt;:
  the ASes that announces subprefixes or the ASes that are the direct provider of the origin AS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;large-IXP&lt;/strong&gt;:
  the ASes that are among large-IXP collaborations are also considered legitimate origins.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;same organization&lt;/strong&gt;:
  the ASes that are from the same organizations.
  the data is obtained from WHOIS database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last step is then to assign a offensive value for each AS:
&lt;strong&gt;the ASes that are not in legitimate set but still announcing the prefixes are assigned with higher offensive value&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;validation&quot;&gt;Validation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The validation of this work is done by sending massive emails (582 in total).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bib entry:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@article{khare2012concurrent,
    author = {Khare, Varun and Ju, Qing and Zhang, Beichuan},
    isbn = {9781450317054},
    pages = {29--35},
    title = {Concurrent Prefix Hijacks : Occurrence and Impacts},
    year = {2012}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://mwzhang.com/reviews/2015/08/khare2012concurrent.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mwzhang.com/reviews/2015/08/khare2012concurrent.html</guid>
        
        <category>BGP</category>
        
        <category>attack</category>
        
        <category>hijack</category>
        
        
        <category>paper review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: Securing BGP - A Literature Survey</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;bgp-threat-model&quot;&gt;BGP Threat Model&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The BGP theats can be categorized by asking the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do we talk? – the TCP channel security&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who am I talking to? – the identity verification&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are you saying? – the message integrity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Should I believe you? – the trust model&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How recent is your info still valid? – TTL for your messages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These questsions essentially includes all the aspects that a communication between 
two BGP routers would have.
If we could secure all of the aspects, 
we are then on the pretty secure side of the war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the design of BGP does not take these aspects into consideration,
and thus creates a set of serious problems.
The consequences include the capability for the attackers to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;eavesdrop on the Internet traffic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;conduct denial of service using invalid messages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;potentially masquerade different entities on the Internet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;steal unused addresses for malicious purposes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Years of efforts has been devoted to secure the BGP and here are some apporaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;securing-bgp&quot;&gt;Securing BGP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Approaches:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;securing-bgp-operations&quot;&gt;Securing BGP Operations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GTSM&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IPSec&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MD5 signature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;securing-bgp-messages&quot;&gt;Securing BGP Messages&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Out of band: DNS or IRV&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;S-BGP, BGPSec&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;soBGP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;psBGP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IRV&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;chained hash function&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SPV&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;signature amortisation and aggregate signatures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;path stability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;securing-data-plane&quot;&gt;Securing data plane&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Issues are that Mao et al. [143] found that up to 8% of the routes advised through control plane channel
do not match the data plane path that the traffic actually took.
Several approaches has been devoted on securing the data-plane security of BGP:
* &lt;em&gt;secure traceroute&lt;/em&gt;
* &lt;em&gt;Faith&lt;/em&gt;
* &lt;em&gt;Listen and Whisper&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;deployment-status&quot;&gt;Deployment Status&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The figure below shows the depoyment status of the existing BGP security approaches.
3 out of 12 approaches has been implemented, and 2 of them were actually deployed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/MOWnd51.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/MOWnd51.png&quot; alt=&quot;deployment&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bib entry:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@article{huston2011securing,
    author = {Huston, Geoff and Rossi, Mattia and Armitage, Grenville},
    issn = {1553-877X},
    journal = {IEEE Communications Surveys \&amp;amp; Tutorials},
    keywords = {BGP,BGP security,Computer Network Protocols,Inter-domain routing security,routing},
    number = {2},
    pages = {199--222},
    title = ,
    volume = {13},
    year = {2011}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://mwzhang.com/reviews/2015/08/huston2011securing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mwzhang.com/reviews/2015/08/huston2011securing.html</guid>
        
        <category>BGP</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
        <category>paper review</category>
        
        <category>bgp</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: An empirical study of behavioral characteristics of spammers: Findings and implications</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;key-idea&quot;&gt;Key Idea&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This paper analyzes the charasteristics of the spammers.
The results include a pretty interesting fact that the spammers use
BGP updates to steal IP addresses to send spams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;findings&quot;&gt;Findings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The behaviors of spammers can help develop the &lt;strong&gt;content-independent&lt;/strong&gt; anti-spam techniques.
This type of techniques is more resistent to the variantion of the spams
and potentially be more accurate than identifying spams through only the content of the messages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authors developed a set of &lt;strong&gt;metrics&lt;/strong&gt; to assess the characteristics of the spammers.
The metrics include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;spam/non-spam ratios of servers:&lt;/strong&gt;
  the majority of the servers are either spam-only or non-spam-only.
  the mixed type of servers are rare.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;statistics of messages across different spammers:&lt;/strong&gt;
  most servers only send a very small amount of spam emails per day
  (less than 10 emails per day is considered small amount)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;arrival patterns of the spam emails across the IP spaces:&lt;/strong&gt;
  most spam emails were sent from a few /8 IP blocks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;**number of mail servers in different networks: **
  86% of the networks have less than 10 spam servers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;active duration of the spam networks:&lt;/strong&gt;
  85% of the spam networks were active for less than 3 days before they went dark&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;correlation with BGP updtes:&lt;/strong&gt;
  the spam emails were sent soon after the short-lived BGP updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bib entry:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@article{duan2011empirical,
    author = {Duan, Zhenhai and Gopalan, Kartik and Yuan, Xin},
    journal = {Computer Communications},
    number = {14},
    pages = {1764--1776},
    publisher = {Elsevier B.V.},
    title = ,
    url = {http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.comcom.2011.03.015},
    volume = {34},
    year = {2011}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://mwzhang.com/reviews/2015/08/duan2011empirical.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mwzhang.com/reviews/2015/08/duan2011empirical.html</guid>
        
        <category>BGP</category>
        
        <category>spammer</category>
        
        <category>attack</category>
        
        
        <category>paper review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: On evaluating BGP routing stress attack</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This paper introduce a new attack inspired from synchronization and resonance in complex system.
The attack is essentially exaust router’s storage processing power and storage capacity,
and cause the routers to restart and reannounce its learned RIB table.
By &lt;strong&gt;carefully select target routers to attack&lt;/strong&gt;, the resonance effect could cause a globally flood of BGP announcements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;evaluation-by-simulation&quot;&gt;Evaluation by Simulation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The method and topology for simulation is shown in the figures below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/nRs9YhL.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/nRs9YhL.png&quot; alt=&quot;topo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/C6AhH7Q.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/C6AhH7Q.png&quot; alt=&quot;method&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cascading-failure&quot;&gt;Cascading Failure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If one AS fails, its neighbors need to withdraw all the routes learned from the failed AS.
The ripple effects will cause a large amount of withdrawal and announcements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bib entry:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@article{deng2010evaluating,
    author = {Deng, Wenping and Zhu, Peidong and Lu, Xicheng and Plattner, Bernhard},
    issn = {17962021},
    journal = {Journal of Communications},
    number = {1},
    pages = {13--22},
    title = {On evaluating BGP routing stress attack},
    volume = {5},
    year = {2010}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://mwzhang.com/reviews/2015/08/deng2010evaluating.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mwzhang.com/reviews/2015/08/deng2010evaluating.html</guid>
        
        <category>BGP</category>
        
        <category>attack</category>
        
        
        <category>paper review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review: ASWatch - An AS Reputation System to Expose Bulletproof Hosting ASes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This paper introduces ASWatch,
a control-plane passive monitoring system that can identify malicious autonomous systems (ASes) with high accuracy.
The system learns features of ASes from the BGP updates and
defines normality using statistic features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;malicious-and-legitimate-ases&quot;&gt;Malicious and Legitimate ASes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authors define the &lt;strong&gt;malicious ASes&lt;/strong&gt; as those who are managed by cyber-criminals,
and with a main purpose of supporting illicit network activities.
The activities include but not limited as phishing, malware distribution, botnets, spamming etc.
The authors also define the term &lt;strong&gt;malicious AS relation&lt;/strong&gt;, 
as the relationship between a malicious AS and its “masking ASes”,
i.e. the providers of the malicious ASes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authors define the &lt;strong&gt;legitiamte ASes&lt;/strong&gt; as those to provide legitimate Internet services.
Note that a legitimate AS could also be abused for malicious activities, 
but the authors consider those cases rare situations and not treat the ASes as malicious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main goal of this paper is to correctly identify the malicious ASes,
and separate them from the legitimate ASes.
The authors use the top 1,000 Alexa websites’ ASes as a ground truth for legitimate ASes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;methodology&quot;&gt;Methodology&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system architecture is shown below.
ASWatch has a typical training and operating cycle of a monitoring system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the training duration,
ASWatch will use the ground truth knowledge and the existing relationship data 
to extract &lt;strong&gt;labeled feature vectors&lt;/strong&gt; for a supervised statistical training.
The trained model will then be used to identify malicious ASes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the operational phase, the ASWatch takes in a sliding window of BGP snapshots,
and using the data to calculate the corresponding features vectors.
Through the comparison of the feature vectors with the learned model,
ASWatch can give out a &lt;strong&gt;bad reputation score&lt;/strong&gt;.
A malicious AS is identified if the bad reputation score is higher than 90%
during the sliding window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/vEk3BCv.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/vEk3BCv.png&quot; alt=&quot;architecture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The detection false positive rate was kept around 5%, 
which the author argue was a pretty good result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/9JuNyCe.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/9JuNyCe.png&quot; alt=&quot;false positive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some main results:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;accuracy ~93.3%&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;three years’ evaluation revealed 72% true positive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;around 50 to 60 days detection before the public media&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;re-wiring features are the most important
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;re-wiring features represents the &lt;strong&gt;instability frequency&lt;/strong&gt; of ASes&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;using only re-wiring features have around the same result&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;without re-wiring feature, the accuracy dropped dramatically&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the results are not sensitive to the parameter tuning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compare to BGP Ranking, ASWatch achieves much better results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/wa981ZW.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/wa981ZW.png&quot; alt=&quot;bgpranking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ASWatch serves as a &lt;strong&gt;ranking system for ASes&lt;/strong&gt;,
uses &lt;strong&gt;passive control-plane&lt;/strong&gt; monitoring data,
relies on &lt;strong&gt;re-wiring features&lt;/strong&gt; to identify malicious ASes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bib entry:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@inproceedings{konte2015aswatch,
    title={ASwatch: An AS Reputation System to Expose Bulletproof Hosting ASes},
    author={Konte, Maria and Perdisci, Roberto and Feamster, Nick},
    booktitle={Proceedings of the 2015 ACM Conference on Special Interest Group on Data Communication},
    pages={625--638},
    year={2015},
    organization={ACM}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://mwzhang.com/reviews/2015/08/knote2015aswatch.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://mwzhang.com/reviews/2015/08/knote2015aswatch.html</guid>
        
        <category>bgp</category>
        
        <category>reputation system</category>
        
        <category>bulletproof</category>
        
        
        <category>paper review</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
